Self Taught & Self Motivated

Introduction

I am **Dyontai Staton**, an engineer since the age of 12. At that age I was developing 2D platform games with C# just to have something of my own to play with my brothers. At the age of 15 I entered the realm of **E-Commerce** and **Web Development**. From that point I started developing & producing numerous eCommerce sites for clients through various freelance contracts. At 16 I had assembled a team of developers to service **Large & Small Businesses** creating, and managing their **Online Presence**.

I've done everything from Designing Sites through Figma to Cloud Deployment of node applications. I'm known for doing the impossible... and then doing it the next day just because I want to \bigcirc

Skills

- Experience: FullStack Development since 2016 & Lead Developer @ Staton Web
 Development
 - Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, PHP, C#
 - Incorporate AGILE / SCRUM Development Process
 - Certified Lead Developer / Programmer With Professional Recognition
 - Managed Numerous High Price Development Contracts
 - Automated Testing With Debugging & Analysis
 - Ability To Train Development Concepts
 - User Requirement Gathering
 - All Skills were Self-taught & Gained From Working With Professional Clients

Education

- ACT Score: 32
- GPA: 3.2

Southern High School, Louisville

Computer Science & Cyber Science Career Pathway | August 2016 - May 2020

- Coding Club August 2019 May 2020
- Beta Club August 2018 May 2020
- Advance Placement August 2016-2020

Self Taught & Self Motivated

Professional Experience

Mightily

June 2021 - Current (Developer)

Eckerts (June 2021 - Aug 2021) https://eckerts.com

Front-end & Back-end Development - Mid to Launch

(Wordpress + SCSS + PHP)

Embroiderers' Guild of America (Aug 2021 - Current) https://egausa.org/

Front-end & Back-end Development - Mid to Ongoing

(Wordpress + SCSS + PHP)

International Coaching Federation (Aug 2021 - Current) https://coachingfederation.org/

Front-end & Back-end Development - Mid to Ongoing

(Wordpress + SCSS + PHP)

KFC (Nov 2021 - May 2021) https://www.kfc.com/

Front-end Development - Contract Based

(React + SCSS)

Omega (Sep 2021 - Dec 2021) https://www.omegap.com/

Front-end & Back-end Development - Start to Finish

(Wordpress + SCSS + PHP)

Metro United Way (Oct 2022 - Nov 2022) https://metrounitedway.org/

Front-end & Back-end Development - Mid to Ongoing

(Wordpress + SCSS + PHP)

Accessia (May 2022 - Aug 2022) https://accessiahealth.org/

Front-end & Backend Development - Start to Finish

(Wordpress + SCSS + PHP + Vue)

Self Taught & Self Motivated

Freelancing Contracts

April 2016 - Current

NowUs.com - Los Angeles California (Dec 2019 - 2021) https://nowus.com

Full Stack Development of Video Streaming Platform - Start to Finish

(Figma + React + Javascript + Node + Redux + Google Cloud + Docker + Sass + GraphQL)

- Manage & Lead Development, Performing Varying Tasks on Contract Basis
- Design Site Front-end Completely Within Figma
- Create & Meet Deadlines For Both Myself + Team
- Communications With Client Company to Determine Client Needs & Design Goals
- Application Optimization Based On A/B Testing
- Documentation & Change-log to keep team up-to-date on changes
- Integrated Open-Source into the project's code base while staying secure.
- Containerized Project to allow for Cloud Deployment
- Team Worked Both Remote & At Office
- Secure PayPal Subscription Payment Integration
- User Account Feature
- Video Streaming Feature With Stream Control
- Possibility Of App Development
- Collaboration with Million Dollar Company
- Automated Email Sender Through Database Triggers
- Facebook Pixel & Google Analytics Integration
- Admin Dashboard with site's videos & user controls.

Client Testimony

" This guy was AMAZING... I would hire him AGAIN and AGAIN. based in the USA... great communicator... perfect written english - I used him to create code for a very unique specific type of website and he hit a home run!!! 100% SATISFIED!!! "



harlanfreedman * 5



United States

This guy was AMAZING... I would hire him AGAIN and AGAIN. based in the USA... great communicator... perfect written english - I used him to create code for a very unique specific type of website and he hit a home run!!! 100% SATISFIED!!!

Published 1 year ago

Self Taught & Self Motivated

Dylights - Louisville Kentucky (Mar 2021 - Current) https://baked-dylights.web.app Full Stack Development of Ecommerce Cookie Shop-Start to Finish

(Figma + React + Javascript + Node + Redux + Google Cloud + Docker + Sass + GraphQL)

- Manage & Lead Development, Performing Varying Tasks on Contract Basis
- Design Site Front-end Completely Within Figma
- Create & Meet Deadlines For Both Myself + Team
- Secure Stripe Payment Integration
- User Account Feature
- Automated Email Sender Through Database Triggers
- Facebook Pixel & Google Analytics Integration
- Admin Dashboard with site's videos & user controls.

Self Taught & Self Motivated

Personal Projects

Staton Web Development

Web & Application Development Freelancing Team of 3 | 2019 - Current

- Managed & Lead Team of Developers
- 56 Finished Contracts With 94% Finished On Time
- Maintained 5 Star Ratings on Freelancer Sites

Client Testimony

" Extremely professional, quick and knowledgeable!"



Extremely professional, quick and knowledgeable!

Published 1 year ago

Staton.cc

Official Site of Staton Web Development

- Made With Nuxt & Firebase
- Database Integration
- FullStack Development
- Optimized SEO Integration
- Bundled With Webpack

Dyontai.com

My Personal Portfolio

- Made With React & Hosted Through Firebase
- It's Simply Just Cool